Being an employee at a company has many challenges – you want job satisfaction, a work-life balance and opportunities for promotion.
在公司做一名员工要面临诸多挑战——你渴望获得工作满足感、实现工作与生活的平衡，还希望拥有晋升机会。
But most of us want a decent financial reward.
但我们大多数人都希望得到不错的物质回报。
We aim to get a good salary to pay for the essential things in life plus a few luxuries.
我们努力赚取高薪，不仅要支付生活必需品的开销，还想购买一些奢侈品。
But when that’s not enough, we have to do the hardest thing in the world – ask our boss for a pay rise!
可当现有的薪水不够用时，我们就不得不做一件世上最难的事——找老板要求加薪！
In some companies, a regular annual pay rise is the norm – all staff get a fixed increase in their monthly pay packet.
在一些公司，固定的年度加薪是常态——所有员工的月薪都会获得固定涨幅。
In other firms, workers might get a bonus to reward them for their efforts or for meeting a target.
而在另一些公司，员工可能会因为工作努力或完成目标而获得奖金。
But for some people, a pay increase is something you have to ask for – and if you don’t ask, you don’t get!
但对有些人来说，加薪是必须自己主动去争取的——你不张口，就什么也得不到！
Wage increases have been a sensitive issue in recent years.
近年来，加薪一直是个敏感话题。
Due to the global economic recession, businesses had to tighten their belts.
受全球经济衰退的影响，企业不得不勒紧裤腰带过日子。
Most public sector pay in the UK, for example, was frozen for two years in 2010, and after that rises were capped at 1% - below the rate of inflation.
比如在英国，2010年大多数公共部门的薪资两年内毫无变化，在那之后，薪资涨幅最高也没有超过1%，这一比例低于通货膨胀率。
But last month the government awarded them a pay rise above the 2% inflation rate so that teachers, for example, will get a 2.75% salary boost.
但上个月，政府为公共部门员工提供了高于2%通胀率的加薪幅度，以教师为例，他们的薪资将上涨2.75%。
That's the equivalent to £1,000 extra a year for those on an average salary.
对于平均薪资水平的人来说，这相当于每年多收入1000英镑。
But not everyone is happy at being given a fixed pay rise – they feel they’re worth more and that they deserve more money.
但并非所有人都满足于固定幅度的加薪——他们认为自己的价值更高，理应获得更多报酬。
It’s not something we should fear “asking for”, says Pip Jamieson, founder of the professional networking site, The Dots.
职业社交网站The Dots的创始人皮普·詹米森表示，要求加薪这件事根本无需畏惧。
She’s told the BBC “No one ever got fired for asking for a pay rise.
她在接受BBC采访时说：“从来没有人会因为要求加薪而被解雇。
In fact, rather the opposite - asking for more money shows ambition and shows you want to stay with the company.”
事实上，恰恰相反——主动要求加薪彰显了你的抱负，也表明你希望继续留在公司发展。”
It’s something BBC Business Reporter Jamie Robertson has been looking into.
BBC商业记者杰米·罗伯逊一直在研究这件事。
He’s found that you need to do your research and find out what kind of pay your job should be getting, perhaps by talking to your Human Resources department.
他发现，你需要先做些功课，弄清楚自己的岗位应得的薪资水平，或许可以咨询人力资源部门。
You’ll need to give good reasons for wanting more money and you’ll still have to keep your increase within your pay grade.
你需要给出加薪的充分理由，而且加薪幅度还得在自己的薪资等级范围内。
Ask for an exact sum and be prepared for some negotiation.
提出明确的加薪数额，并做好谈判的准备。
Of course, if you can’t get more cash then there are other perks you could ask for, such as flexible working or more time off.
当然，如果你无法争取到更多现金报酬，还可以要求其他福利，比如弹性工作制或者更多休假时间。
But if that gets you nowhere and your boss won’t budge, maybe it’s time to quit and find a new job?
但如果这些努力都毫无进展，老板也丝毫不让步，那或许就该辞职，另谋高就了？